Tommy Lau

FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

DETAILS

tlau425@gmail.com (646) 894-7191 linkedin.com/in/tommyl425 github.com/tlau425

PROFILE

Fullstack web developer with a passion to constantly learn new technology and problem solving. Through my experiences from two immersive bootcamps, I excel in mentoring others and filling leadership roles when necessary. I also bring strong communication skills and open-mind thinking to work collaboratively in a team.

LANGUAGES

JavaScript, Ruby, Python, HTML, CSS, SCSS

Frameworks / Libraries

React, Node, Express, Ruby on Rails, Redux, Typescript

Tools & Platforms

PostgreSQL, MySQL, Bootstrap, JQuery, Socket.IO, Git, Jira, Agile Development, APIs / Web APIs, Auth, OAuth, Heroku, Jest,

EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer | BrainStation

DEC 2022 - APR 2023, NEW YORK, NY

- Review code and grade projects based on visual appearance, responsiveness, functionality, and code quality (HTML, SASS, JavaScript, RESTful APIs, and Git).
- Reinforced student learning of skills and materials through daily check-ins, informal assessments, and observations.
- Provide thorough lectures to ensure students fully grasp and understand technical concepts in a fast-paced environment.
- Offered position among 30 students due to being the most suitable candidate.

Sales Representative | Spectrum

NOV 2017 - NOV 2018, QUEENS, NY

- Developed and maintained over 600 new and existing customers and communities each month by offering best-in-class telecommunication services through door-to-door solicitation of new prospective customers.
- Accomplished a department milestone of most sales made for the month in the NorthEast region.
- Mentored colleagues and newly hired representatives with telecommunication knowledge and marketing communication skills to increase performance and sales.

PROJECTS

Full Stack Software Engineer | Meal Buddy - Demo

A networking platform for users to organize and seamlessly meet people at Yelp locations.

- Auth implementation using JWT and BCrypt ensures that the user's login information is secure and encrypted.
- Real-time messaging for connected accounts using the Socket.IO library. Users have separate chat rooms for each connected user.
- Dynamic search query to the Yelp Fusion API for customized requests based on input from anywhere worldwide.
- Google Maps Platform API utilized for visually displaying restaurant and reservation locations with coordinate based markers.

Front-end Developer | 1st Place Hackathon

24-hour hackathon hosted by BrainStation with a problem space of finding the true cost of living in New York.

- Implemented an interactive heat map using Tableau for viewing consumer satisfaction based on JSON data.
- Collaborated with UI/UX designers and data scientists to develop a comprehensive presentation consisting of user stories, Figma designs, data charts, and a web application.
- Dynamic rendering of data to easily show users if they're paying more or less than the total average cost based on their zip code.

Full Stack Software Engineer | Which Way?

A dynamic Javascript memory game where users have to use the arrow keys to repeat a sequence of movements that gets longer with progression.

- Efficient handling of asynchronous events such as timer, actions, and pausing.
- Persisting scoreboard database for users with the highest scores using Ruby and Postgres.
- Hardest difficulty will have a reverse feature that will require you to input the opposite arrow key shown.

EDUCATION

BrainStation | Diploma, Web Development

SEP 2022 - DEC 2022, NEW YORK, NY

Flatiron School | Diploma, Software Engineering

MAR 2019 - JUL 2019, NEW YORK, NY

Brooklyn College | Computer Science

JAN 2014 - 2016, BROOKLYN, NY